# Aidan Mac Creary

Mobile:086 8251398

Email: aidanmac@gmail.com

OVERVIEW Having worked in a variety of large and smaller companies I am used to working both independently and in teams. I have a flexible attitude and have experience in diagnosing issues and implementing solutions with little time or resources while minimising downtime and maintaining service levels.

#### **EDUCATION**

## National College of Ireland (2014 to 2015)

A 1 year Higher Diploma in Cloud Computing completed in May 2015. This course to date has included SQL Database development, Software Design in Java, Object Orientated Software Design, Computer Architecture and Web Design which includes HTML5, CSS layout and Javascript including JQuery, BootStrap and AJAX.

# Institute of Technology Tallaght (2006 to 2011)

5 year Bachelor of Engineering (Honours) in Electronic Engineering. I passed with first class honours in June 2011. My final year project was to create a timing and instruction accurate Z80 processor using VHDL. This course included such subjects as Digital Microprocessor Design, Analysis of Analogue Communication, Software Development in C++, Engineering Software and Computer Networking.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## Xilinx Inc. (2012 to 2014 on contract, 2015 to Date)

I work as a Product Application Engineer in the Worldwide Technical Support software team to provide highly technical time critical customer support to developers using ISE and Vivado which involves the use of VHDL, Verilog and TCL scripting. During my time in Xilinx I have twice won an award as the PAE with the highest satisfaction rating.

# Cost Plus Sofas (2011)

A part time job where as part of the customer services team I was responsible for customer relations, organising deliveries, cashing up and sales.

### Folens Management Services Limited (2001 to 2010)

During my time in FMSL I provided day to day IT support including the configuration of Windows, Mac and Linux clients and servers. I was also responsible for the maintenance and backup of the file, print, and database servers both physical and the VMWare and VirtualBox virtual machines in Ireland and the UK.

I used a combination of Visual Basic 6, Microsoft SQL and Crystal Reports to develop multiple systems including phone system maintenance software which provided an interface to the Nortel phone system to allow for modifications and reporting and software to interface with barcode scanning hardware in order to reduce shipping errors and to automate the returns process.

The UK and Irish costing systems were developed in house and these systems recorded the progress of books being developed e.g. project details, time recorded in development, purchase orders and invoices.

### Folens Publishers (1998 to 2001)

I worked as one half of a two man team on the development of FOPS (Folens Orders Processing System) as well as setting up and managing the IT infrastructure. This included networking, hardware and software support as well as the research and development of multiple software projects.

### **Digisource (1997 to 1998)**

I was instrumental in setting up and supporting Digisource's on demand print service, including configuration of the networks and infrastructure

## OTHER EXPERIENCE Ericsson Ireland (2012)

Completed an internship and work experience in Ericsson as part of a Masters programme to develop SAP Business Object Universes, including Microsoft SQL databases and Test Driven Development.

#### Xilinx Ireland Ltd (2011)

One of four undergraduates asked to present our final year project at the Xilinx Research Labs Open Day for their Programmable Logic Systems Workshop.

### Bank Of New York Mellon (2010)

As one of six Irish interns, we worked to develop a new security system to protect sensitive customer and bank data. This involved working with colleagues of all levels both locally and internationally.

OTHER SKILLS In IT Tallaght, I worked with 8053 and Z80 assembly, Basic Stamp chips, Java, C and C++ to develop projects.

I am an Oracle Certified Professional, Java SE6 Programmer.

I achieved an MCSE +I and have worked with Visual Basic 6, MS SQL, MS Exchange, IBM AIX, Red Hat and Suse Linux, Networking, Virtualisation, Crystal Reports, Excel, Access, Word.

## **OTHER INTERESTS**

Motorcycle mechanics and restoration, building computers, electronics, archery.

**REFERENCES** Available on request.